Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers 1822-1998 (bulk 1920-1968)
ML31.C39
Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968
approximately 7,900 items 161 containers 71.0 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
This collection consists of materials related to the professional and personal activities of composer Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco. It contains holograph music manuscripts, printed scores, libretti, writings, correspondence, business files, photographs, programs, clippings, and other items that document the life of this influential composer.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959--Correspondence.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968--Archives.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968--Correspondence.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968--Criticism and interpretation.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968--Photographs.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Merchant of Venice.; Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Selections.; Dallapiccola, Luigi, 1904-1975--Correspondence.; Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-1987--Correspondence.; Moldenhauer, Hans--Correspondence.; Pizzetti, Ildebrando, 1880-1968--Correspondence.; Rossi, Nick, 1924-2000--Correspondence.; Rossi, Nick, 1924-2000. Catalogue of works by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco.; Rota, Nino, 1911-1979--Correspondence.; Segovia, Andrés, 1893-1987--Correspondence.; Strozzi, Memmi--Correspondence.; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957--Correspondence.
Organizations
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.
Subjects
Composers--Italy--Correspondence.; Film composers--United States.; Motion picture music.
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents)
Administrative Information
Provenance
Mario and Clara Castelnuovo-Tedesco first deposited music manuscripts at the Library of Congress in June 1966. A second agreement was signed in October 1970 and subsequent deposits from Clara continued until 1978. In February 2000, Lisbeth and Lorenzo Castelnuovo-Tedesco donated the remainder of the present scores, papers, and other materials to the Library.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Sound recordings have been transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division.
Related Material
A significant quantity of holograph manuscript scores, formerly on deposit, are cataloged in ML96.C34. Scores for several of the composer's works for violin are found in the
Jascha Heifetz Collection
(ML31.H4a). Additional scores of varying instrumentation are housed in the
Moldenhauer Archives
(ML31.M6).
Access and Restrictions
The Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers are open to research. Correspondence between Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco and his brother, Ugo Castelnuovo-Tedesco, from 1940-1947 is restricted until 2020. Two additional boxes of materials related to guitarist Andrés Segovia, principally correspondence and performance reviews, are also restricted. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1895 April 3 Born, Florence, Italy
1909-1914 Studies at Instituto musicale Luigi Cherubini, Florence
1915 Composes war song, Fuori i barbari
1918 Receives "diploma di composizione" from Liceo musicale, Bologna
1923 Marries Clara Forti
1925 Son Pietro born
1926 Premiere performance of first opera, La mandragola, in Venice
1930 Son Lorenzo born
1931 Composes violin concerto, I profeti, for Jascha Heifetz
1932 Meets guitarist Andrés Segovia and begins composing for the guitar
1933 I profeti premiered by Arturo Toscanini and Jascha Heifetz in New York
1935 Composes incidental music for Savonarola
1938 Castelnuovo-Tedesco's work banned from radio in Italy
1939 Composes first guitar concerto for Andrés Segovia
1939 July Leaves Italy for the United States and takes up residence in Larchmont, NY
1940 Mother Noemi dies
1940 Travels to California and begins composing music for Hollywood film soundtracks
1943 Composes Sacred Service for Sabbath Eve
1944 Collaborates with Schoenberg, Stravinsky, Milhaud, and others on the Genesis suite
1946 Becomes a citizen of the United States
1953 Composes first work in a series of greeting cards on the names of dedicatees (op. 159 and 170)
1956 Composes opera after Shakespeare's The Merchant of Venice
1958 The Merchant of Venice wins the Davide Campari Prize – Concorso Internazionale La Scala
1959 Named distinguished guest professor at Michigan State University and lectures on the history of opera
1960 Composes the song cycle, Platero y yo, after the poetry of Jimenez
1961 Premiere performance of The Merchant of Venice at La Scala
1968 March 16 Dies, Beverly Hills, CA
Scope and Content Note
The Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers span the period 1822-1998, with the majority of the materials dating from 1920-1968. The collection includes holograph and copyist music manuscripts, printed music, libretti, writings, personal and family correspondence, business files, photographs, programs, reviews, biographical materials, film music materials, and an assortment of books owned by the composer.
"Music" consists principally of holograph or copyist manuscripts and printed scores of Castelnuovo-Tedesco's compositions and arrangements. Many of these scores, especially the photocopied manuscripts, contain pencil or ink annotations in the hand of the composer. Works with opus numbers are distinguished from those without numbers and instrumentation is identified wherever possible. Much of this supplementary descriptive information is taken from the Catalogue of Works by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco by Nick Rossi. Included among the manuscripts are scores by students of Castelnuovo-Tedesco and various other composers, including Vittorio Rieti, Fernando Liuzzi, and Miklos Rozsa. Researchers are also encouraged to examine additional Castelnuovo-Tedesco manuscript materials in the Library of Congress that are closely affiliated with those from this collection. Nearly two hundred holograph scores deposited by the composer and his wife prior to 1979 are cataloged in ML96.C34, while other materials are located in the
Jascha Heifetz Collection
(ML31.H4a) and the
Moldenhauer Archives
(ML31.M6). Detailed references to these works are provided in the container list.
Castelnuovo-Tedesco's working scripts for operas, oratorios, ballets, incidental music for plays, and song cycles are arranged by opus number or title under "Libretti". Most of these materials are original adaptations of other texts: plays and poetry by Shakespeare, Savonarola, Wilde, and Alfieri, as well as the Bible. There is also a collection of texts for his abandoned Reconstruction Symphony. Scripts for films are located with the "Film music materials" series. "Writings" indexes Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco’s published and unpublished literary works, as well as numerous substantial pieces about him by other authors. It includes drafts of books Una vita di musica, La penna perduta, and Under the Sign of Orpheus, as well as articles, essays, lectures, program notes, interviews, work lists, and musings on a variety of musical subjects. La sua fede, a bound volume of interviews with Clara Castelnuovo-Tedesco, and a revised, annotated copy of the Rossi Catalogue are standouts among the various writings about the composer.
"Correspondence" is categorically designated as "general" or "family," with the former arranged alphabetically within by correspondent. The general file chiefly contains letters to Castelnuovo-Tedesco or members of his family, with occasional attached drafts or copies of the composer's own letters. Notable correspondents include Ernest Bloch, Jascha Heifetz, Hans Moldenhauer, Ildebrando Pizzeti, Andrés Segovia, Arturo Toscanini, and many others. The largest of these files consists of letters between conductor and scholar Nick Rossi and Castelnuovo-Tedesco, as well as his family. Researchers are also advised to examine ML94 for additional letters between the composer and Pizzeti, Ernst Toch, Darius Milhaud, and others. Castelnuovo's handwritten logs of correspondence from 1947-1968 (box 128, folder 27) are especially useful points for departure. Family correspondence contains letters both to and from parents Amedeo and Noemi, sons Pietro and Lorenzo, wife Clara, and other extended family members and friends. Correspondence from Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco appears first under each heading.
"Business files" contains files related to publishers, concert agents, recording companies, and film studios, arranged alphabetically by corporate name. Materials include contracts, correspondence, royalty statements, and receipts. A substantial portion of this material is between Castelnuovo-Tedesco’s heirs and the publishers. "Photographs" portray diverse experiences from the lives of various Castelnuovo-Tedesco family members. These images are loosely arranged by date, subject, or opus number. Included are portraits of Castelnuovo-Tedesco, snapshots of the composer with distinguished musical personalities (Cesar Cui, Walter Gieseking, Jascha Heifetz, and Igor Stravinsky), and production photographs from The Merchant of Venice, Aucassin et Nicolette, The Song of Songs, and other stage works.
Concert performances by Castelnuovo-Tedesco and performances of his works by others are documented in "Programs." Many are annotated by performers or include attached reviews. These programs continue for nearly thirty years after Castelnuovo-Tedesco’s death, culminating in the 1995 centenary concerts. Although the majority are arranged chronologically, a small subset are organized by performer or subject. "Reviews" contains clippings, telegrams, promotional materials, and other documents associated with performances of specific opus-numbered works. There are also several small scrapbooks related to particular works or concert tours, such as Castelnuovo-Tedesco’s 1924 concert tour as an accompanist to singer Salomea Kruceniski. Similar documents are also found in the "Merchant of Venice materials," a series of subject files directly related to its 1961 and 1966 staged productions.
"Biographical materials" is a topical array of financial, educational, military, and other personal documents related to Castelnuovo-Tedesco and his family members. It contains correspondence regarding the composer's emigration from Italy to the United States in 1939, including letters to Mussolini, D’Annunzio, and Alessandro Pavolini. Also included are naturalization papers, passports, datebooks, address books, lists of students, newspaper clippings, and notebooks from Castelnuovo-Tedesco's days as a student in Italy. "Film music materials" is a subject file of assorted scripts and materials, some annotated, related to motion pictures for which Castelnuovo-Tedesco composed music. The final series, "Bound materials owned by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco," contains annotated, inscribed, or specially bound books and scores that belonged to the composer.
Arrangement of the Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers
The Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco Papers are organized in 12 series:
Music, 1905-1968
Libretti, 1920-1965
Writings, 1919-1997
Correspondence, 1908-1998
Business Files, 1915-1997
Photographs, circa 1900-1970s
Programs, 1909-1995
Reviews, 1914-1996
Merchant of Venice Materials, 1954-1966
Biographical Materials, 1899-1977
Film Music Materials, 1941-1959
Bound Materials Owned by Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco, 1822-1965
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006579409
Container List
- Music, 1905-1968 (Box 1-106)
  - Works with opus number, 1910-1968
    - Op. 1: Cielo di Settembre (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 45
      - Printed score (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Op. 1: Cielo di Settembre (orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Op. 2: Questo fu il carro della morte (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 132
      - Printed score (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Op. 3: Le Roi Loys (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 136
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Op. 3: Le Roi Loys (voice, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Op. 4: Ninna nanna (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 127
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Op. 4: Ninna nanna (voice, orchestra)
      - Printed piano-conductor score (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Parts (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Op. 5: Fuori i barbari (voice, piano)
      - 2 printed piano-vocal scores, Laid in: 2 postcards with printed text (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Op. 6: Stella cadenti (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Op. 7: Coplas (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Op. 7: Coplas (voice, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 63/1)
      - Parts (Box-folder 2/3-6)
    - Op. 8: Briciole (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 57 (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Op. 9: Il raggio verde (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 42
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Op. 10: Signorine (violin, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 27
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/3)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Op. 11: 3 fioretti di San Francesco (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Op. 11: 3 fioretti di San Francesco (voice, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 3/5)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 63/2)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Op. 12: Alghe (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Op. 12: Alghe (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Op. 13: I naviganti (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Op. 14: Girotondo dei golosi (voice, piano)
      - 3 printed piano-vocal scores (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Op. 15: Ritmi (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Op. 16: Capitan Fracassa (violin, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 49
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Op. 17: Cipressi (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 67
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/5)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Op. 17: Cipressi (orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 63/3)
    - Op. 17: Cipressi (orchestra; 1940 version)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 4/7)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 63/4-5)
      - Parts, see also ML96.C34 no. 67 (Box-folder 4/8-13)
    - Op. 18: La sirenetta e il pesce turchino (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Op. 18: La sirenetta e il pesce turchino (2 pianos)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Op. 18: La sirenetta e il pesce turchino (orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 63/6)
    - Op. 19: Cantico (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Op. 20: La mandragola (voices, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score, Laid in: Holograph manuscript libretto; [43] p.; Laid in: Holograph manuscript notes and lists of song durations; [9] p.; see ML96.C34 no. 99
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Op. 20: La mandragola. Prologo (voices, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Op. 20: La mandragola (voices, orchestra; 1928 version)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 5/5)
      - Printed libretto (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Op. 21: Vitalba e biancospino (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 46
      - Printed score (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Op. 22: L'infinito (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Op. 23: Sera (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see also ML96.C34 no. 141 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Op. 24: 33 Shakespeare songs (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 6/4)
      - Printed piano-vocal scores, Incomplete J. and W. Chester sets (Box-folder 6/5-7)
    - Op. 24: 33 Shakespeare songs. Sea-murmurs [i.e. Arise] (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Op. 24: 33 Shakespeare songs. Tango [i.e. Two maids wooing] (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/2)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Op. 24: 33 Shakespeare songs. Three songs from As you like it (voice, harp or piano, strings)
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 7/3)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 63/7)
      - Parts (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Op. 24: 33 Shakespeare songs. Arise (voice, guitar)
      - 2 holograph manuscript scores (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Op. 24: 33 Shakespeare songs. Seals of love (voice, guitar)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Op. 25: Epigrafe (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 106
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Op. 26: Piccino piccio (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Op. 27: Ballata (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 102
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Op. 28: La barba bianca (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 103
      - 2 printed piano-vocal scores (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Op. 29: 2 preghiere per i bimbi d'Italia (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 129
      - 2 printed piano-vocal scores (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Op. 30: Alt Wien (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Op. 30: Alt Wien (2 pianos)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Op. 30: Duo danze (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 7/14)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Op. 31: Concerto italiano (violin, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score, see Jascha Heifetz Collection, ML31.H4a
      - Printed full score (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Printed full score (Box-folder 63/8)
      - Printed piano-violin score (Box-folder 8/1)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Op. 32: Piedigrotta 1924 (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 44
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Op. 32: Notturno e tarantella (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Op. 32: Notturno e tarantella (2 pianos)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Op. 33: Le stagioni (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 43
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Op. 34: Notturno adriatico (violin, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 50
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/6)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Op. 35: 4 scherzi per musica (voice, piano; 1st series)
      - Printed piano-vocal score, see also ML96.C34 no. 136 (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Op. 35: 4 scherzi per musica (voice, piano; 2nd series)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 139
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Op. 36: 1830 (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Op. 37: Le danze del Re David (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Op. 38: Indian serenade (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Op. 39: Bacco in Tuscano (voices, chorus, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score, see ML96.C34 no. 54
    - Op. 40: Drei Heine Lieder, I Heft (voice, piano)
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Op. 41: 4 sonetti da La vita nova (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 143
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Op. 42: 3 sonnets from the Portuguese (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 71
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Op. 43: Tre corali su melodie ebraiche (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 63
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Op. 44: Tre poemi campestri (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Op. 45: Cadix (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 65
      - Printed piano-vocal score, see also ML96.C34 no. 65 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Op. 46: Concerto in sol (piano, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score, see ML96.C34 no. 4
      - Printed piano score (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Op. 47: I nottambuli (violoncello, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 10/1)
      - Violoncello part (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Op. 47: I nottambuli (violoncello, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 10/2)
      - Photocopied holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 64/1)
      - Manuscript full score (Box-folder 64/1)
      - Parts (Box-folder 10/3-8)
    - Op. 48: Variazioni sinfoniche (violin, orchestra)
      - Holograph manuscript full score, see ML96.C34 no. 9
      - Printed piano-violin score (Box-folder 11/1)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Op. 49: Trio in sol (violin, violoncello, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 33
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/2)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Parts (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Op. 50: Sonata (violoncello, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/4)
      - Violoncello part (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Op. 51: Sonata (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 56
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Op. 52: Ore sole (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 128
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Op. 53: Chant hébraique (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/7)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Op. 53: Chant hébraique (violoncello, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/8)
      - Violoncello part (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Op. 53: Chant hébraique (double bass, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score for double bass (Box-folder 11/9)
    - Op. 54: Passatempi (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Op. 55: Tre vocalizzi (voice, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score, see ML96.C34 no. 150
      - Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Op. 55: Tre vocalizzi (violin, piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 11/12)
      - Violin part (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Op. 56: Sonata quasi una fantasia (violin, piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 28
      - Printed score (Box-folder 64/2)
    - Op. 57: B-a-ba (piano)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Op. 58: Quartetto in sol (string quartet)
      - Printed score (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Parts (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Op. 59: Crinoline (piano)
      - Holograph manuscript score, see ML96.C34 no. 41